Finding Aid for the The Andrew Nelson Lytle Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
- Series and Subseries Descriptions
  - Series VII. Biographical/Personal Information, 1892-1987
    Biographical and personal information is included in the seventh series. This series contains information regarding clippings, financial information, invitations, documents relating to the Monteagle Sunday School Assembly, 65 photographs, recipes, student days, and travels. A few folders containing fragmented material are also included.
  - Series VIII. Family Papers, 1882-1962
    This series concerns Lytle’s family. The family papers series has material such as clippings, diaries, family documents, financial information, genealogical documents, insurance, legal documents, and fragments that concerns Lytle’s family.
  - Series IX. Writings By Others, N.D.
    This series comprises of numerous writings others have sent to Andrew Lytle to read. Documents have a broad range of genres and cover many subject areas. Documents within this series are alphabetized by the creator of the work. This series contains oversize material that is a long galley of a manuscript by Katherine Anne Porter.
  - Series X. Envelopes, 1928-1988
    Envelopes from correspondence make up this series.
- Series I. Correspondence
  - Outgoing, Jun. 26, 1921 – Oct. 5, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Outgoing, Oct. 29, 1956 – N.D. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Incoming: Adams, Tom E. – Agar, Herbert (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Incoming: Agar, Herbert – Alvord, Carl G. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Incoming: Ames, Archie & Elizabeth – Baker (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Incoming: Balch, Earle (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Incoming: Ball – Barr, Stringfellow (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Incoming: Barrett – Bennett (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Incoming: Berger, Lowe – Boyle, Sarah Patton (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Incoming: Bragg, John T. – Brent, D.K. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Incoming: Brent, D.K. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Incoming: Britt – Cairnie, Gordon (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Incoming: Caldwell, John W. – Carlson, Thomas M. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Incoming: Carrick – Chamberlain (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Incoming: Chambers, Laurance. (1 of 4) (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Incoming: Chambers, Laurance. (2 of 4) (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Incoming: Chambers, Laurance. (3 of 4) (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Incoming: Chambers, Laurance. (4 of 4) (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Incoming: Chambliss, Joe – Chitty, E.N. (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Incoming: Clark, C.D. – Clark, Renie (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Incoming: Clark, S.T. (1 of 3) (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Incoming: Clark, S.T. (2 of 3) (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Incoming: Clark, S.T. (3 of 3) (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Incoming: Clark, W. – Cowan, Thomas C. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Incoming: Coward – Darrow, G.M. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Incoming: Davidson, Donald. (1 of 2) (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Incoming: Davidson, Donald. (2 of 2) (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Incoming: De Bellis, Jack. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Incoming: De Voto – Dewey (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Incoming: Dickey, James. (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Incoming: Dunlap, Dick. (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Incoming: Dyer – Elliott, William Yandell (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Incoming: Ellis – Erskine, Albert (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Incoming: Esler, Bun. (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Incoming: Esler, Juliet. – Folk, N.D.P. (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Incoming: Ford, Jessee Hill – Frederick (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Incoming: Frederickson, Alan. (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Incoming: Freeman – Gerber, Merrill Joan (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Incoming: Gerety, Julia Meek – Goodnow (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Incoming: Gordon, Caroline. (1 of 2) (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Incoming: Gordon, Caroline. (2 of 2) (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Incoming: Gordon, J.M. – Greever (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Incoming: Griffis, Jock. (1 of 2) (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Incoming: Griffis, Jock. (2 of 2) (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Incoming: Guerard - Guy (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Incoming: Haight, George. (1 of 7) (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Incoming: Haight, George. (2 of 7) (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Incoming: Haight, George. (3 of 7) (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Incoming: Haight, George. (4 of 7) (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Incoming: Haight, George. (5 of 7) (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Incoming: Haight, George. (6 of 7) (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Incoming: Haight, George. (7 of 7) (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Incoming: Haight, Justine. – Hamel, Charles Scott (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Incoming: Hamilton, F.P. – Hay, John. (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Incoming: Hay, T.R. – Hetz (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Incoming: Hetrick, Lawrence. (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Incoming: Hills – Hooper, Bett (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Incoming: Hoover, Charles – Howard (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Incoming: Howell, Isabell – Hughes, John Davis (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Incoming: Hullender, Tony – Jerrold, Douglas. (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Incoming: Jerrold, Douglas. – Kemp, Edward (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Incoming: Kirby-Smith, Tommy – Kirkpatrick, Smith. (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Incoming: Kirkpatrick, Smith. – Krey, Laura. (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Incoming: Krey, Laura. – Lawrence (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Incoming: Leatherman, LeRoy. (1 of 4) (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Incoming: Leatherman, LeRoy. (2 of 4) (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Incoming: Leatherman, LeRoy. (3 of 4) (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Incoming: Leatherman, LeRoy. (4 of 4) (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Incoming: Lincoln, Porter A. – Long, Grady McCarty (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Incoming: Longino, Hinton F. – Mannon, Jessica. (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Incoming: Mannon, Jessica. – McConnell, Tom (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Incoming: McCrady, Edward – McDowell, David. (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Incoming: McDowell, David. – McDowell, Martha. (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Incoming: McGehee, Louise – Middleton, David. (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Incoming: Middleton, David. – Milton, George, F. (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Incoming: Milton, George F. – Montgomery, Marion (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Incoming: Moore, Edward – Mueller, Margot (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Incoming: Murfree, Cornelia W. – Northouse, Cameron (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Incoming: O’Brien, Jake – Owsely, Frank. (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Incoming: Owsely, Frank. – Owsely, Harriet. (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Incoming: Pace, Rosalind – Perry, Marvin, B., Jr. (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Incoming: Perry, Marvin, B., Jr. – Porter, Katherine Anne (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Incoming: Porter, Katherine Anne (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Incoming: Porter, Katherine Anne – Radford, Manson (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Incoming: Radford, Manson. – Ransom, John Crowe (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Incoming: Ransom, John Crowe – Reid, Laura Caldwell (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Incoming: Reid, Laura Caldwell. – Roche, George C., III (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Incoming: Rochlet, Morse. – Ryan, Steven T. (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Incoming: Salaita, George D. – Smith, Ron. (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Incoming: Smith, Stephen Page. – Spears, Monroe K. (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Incoming: Spears, Monroe K. – Staden, Henry V. (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Incoming: Staden, Henry V. – Stillman, Chauncey (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Incoming: Stirling, W.L. – Street, Oliver D. (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Incoming: Street, Oliver D. – Sweet (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Incoming: Tate, Allen. (1 of 9) (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Incoming: Tate, Allen. (2 of 9) (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Incoming: Tate, Allen. (3 of 9) (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Incoming: Tate, Allen. (4 of 9) (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Incoming: Tate, Allen. (5 of 9) (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Incoming: Tate, Allen. (6 of 9) (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Incoming: Tate, Allen. (7 of 9) (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Incoming: Tate, Allen. (8 of 9) (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Incoming: Tate, Allen. (9 of 9) (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Incoming: Tate, Helen. – Taylor, Peter. (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Incoming: Taylor-Hall, Mary Ann – Van Zandt, Knox (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Incoming: Venuti, E. – Warren, Cinina (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Incoming: Warren, Robert Penn (1 of 3) (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Incoming: Warren, Robert Penn (2 of 3) (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Incoming: Warren, Robert Penn (3 of 3) (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Incoming: Weyman, William – Wills, Jesse (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Incoming: Wilson, James Southall – Wright, Whittier (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Incoming: Wright, Whittier – Young, James M. (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Incoming: Young, R.J. – Young, Stark (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Incoming: Young, Stark – Ziegner, Herman (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Family-Outgoing, 1920 – 1924 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Family-Outgoing, 1924 – 1932 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Family-Outgoing, 1932 – 1938 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Family-Outgoing, 1938 – 1939 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Family-Outgoing, 1939 – 1943 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Family-Outgoing, 1943 – 1954 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Family-Outgoing, 1954 – 1958 and Undated (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Family-Incoming: Amason, J.L. – Barker, Edna L. (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Family-Incoming: Barker, Edna L. – Barker, Edna Moss (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Family-Incoming: Barker, Edna Moss – Barton, Lala (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Family-Incoming: Beard, William E. – Chambers, Julia Lytle (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Family-Incoming: Chaput, Renee – Darwin, James (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Family-Incoming: Darwin, James – Darwin, Polly Lytle (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Family-Incoming: Darwin, Polly Lytle (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Family-Incoming: Darwin, Polly Lytle (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Family-Incoming: Darwin, Polly Lytle – Drake, Sallie (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Family-Incoming: Dudley & Michener – Gordon, Caroline (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Family-Incoming: Gordon, Caroline – Haight, Justine (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Family-Incoming: Haight, Justine – Jackson, Walter C. (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Family-Incoming: Jackson, Walter C. (1 of 4) (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Family-Incoming: Jackson, Walter C. (2 of 4) (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Family-Incoming: Jackson, Walter C. (3 of 4) (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Family-Incoming: Jackson, Walter C. (4 of 4) (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Family-Incoming: Jerry – Lory, J.H. (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Family-Incoming: Lytle, Edna Barker (1 of 5) (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Family-Incoming: Lytle, Edna Barker (2 of 5) (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Family-Incoming: Lytle, Edna Barker (3 of 5) (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Family-Incoming: Lytle, Edna Barker (4 of 5) (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Family-Incoming: Lytle, Edna Barker (5 of 5) (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Family-Incoming: Lytle, Jesse – Lytle, Lillie Belle (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Family-Incoming: Lytle, Lillie Belle (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Family-Incoming: Lytle, Lillie Langdon – Lytle, Robert L. (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Family-Incoming: Lytle, Robert L. – Lytle, Tom B. (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Family-Incoming: Manning, Margaret – Nelson, George A. (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Family-Incoming: Nelson, George A. – Nelson, Jos. Hewlett (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Family-Incoming: Nelson, Jos. Hewlett – Nelson, Mary (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Family-Incoming: Nelson, Mary (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Family-Incoming: Nelson, Mary – Nelson, Mollie (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Family-Incoming: Nelson, Mollie – Pierce, Emma (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Family-Incoming: Pierce, Emma – Rodriguez, Alfonso A. (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Family-Incoming: Rodriguez, Alfonso A. – Smith, George M. (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Family-Incoming: Smith, George M. – Sneed, Rebecca (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Family-Incoming: Sparks, Ingram – Thompson, John C. (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Family-Incoming: Webster, Allie C. – Youngburg, Maurice (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Unidentified: B. – Mildred (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Unidentified: Ric – Virginia, and Unidentified (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Family Unidentified: Bess – J.B.S. (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Family Unidentified: Suzanne & Sara, and Unidentified (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Cards: Postcards (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Cards: Christmas, Birthday, and Thank you (1 of 2) (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Cards: Christmas, Birthday, and Thank you (2 of 2) (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Cards: Baby Gift, Congratulations (Pamela Lytle, 1941) (Box 9, Folder 1)
- Series II. Writings
  - Poetry-Published (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - “Edward Graves”, 1 page typed manuscript, published, 1925 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Poetry-Unpublished (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - “The House on the Side of the Hill”, 1 page typed manuscript, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Prose-Biography (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Bedford Forrest and His Critter Company (1 of 26). Outline, 3 pages typed manuscript with holograph corrections. (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Prose-Biography (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Bedford Forrest and His Critter Company (2 of 26). Front matter (title pages, divisions of book, chapters) 5 pages typed manuscript with holograph corrections. (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Prose-Biography (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Bedford Forrest and His Critter Company (3 of 26). Prologue “Under the Vine and Fig Tree” Pages 1-3, 1-3, 1-2, typed manuscript with holograph corrections. (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Prose-Biography (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Bedford Forrest and His Critter Company (4 of 26). Chapter 1, pages [1]-6, 3-7, typed manuscript with holograph corrections. Titled “A Basket of Chickens.” (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Prose-Biography (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Bedford Forrest and His Critter Company (5 of 26). Chapter 2, pages [1]-10, 3, 5, 6-8, 10-11, 13 (plus three unnumbered pages) holograph and typed manuscript, with holograph corrections. Titled “The Wilderness Road”. (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Prose-Biography (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Bedford Forrest and His Critter Company (6 of 26). Chapter 3, pages 14-17, one numbered page, 20-25, 4, typed manuscript with holograph corrections. Titled “Chapter III.” (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Prose-Biography (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Bedford Forrest and His Critter Company (7 of 26). Chapter 4, pages 29-43, 16 (plus 2 unnumbered pages), typed manuscript with holograph corrections. Titled “Chapter IV. (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Prose-Biography (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Bedford Forrest and His Critter Company (8 of 26). Chapter 5, pages 44-62, 50- 51, 18, 67 (plus 4 unnumbered pages), typed manuscript with holograph corrections. Titled variously “Chapter V,” “Assembly is Bugled on the Western Front,” “Donelson-A Tragedy of Errors,” “Gray Lines Cross The Cumberland,” “Fort Donelson.” (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Prose-Biography (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Bedford Forrest and His Critter Company (9 of 26). Chapter 6, pages 63-68, typed manuscript with holograph corrections. Titled “The Blue Racer Circles, and the Rattler Coils, in the Tennessee Bottoms.” (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Prose-Biography (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Bedford Forrest and His Critter Company (10 of 26). Chapter 7, pages 70-82, 3 (plus 4 unnumbered pages), typed manuscript with holograph corrections. Titled “Capitulation... To A Picket Fence,” and “Capitulation... To A Rail Fence.” (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Prose-Biography (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Bedford Forrest and His Critter Company (11 of 26). Chapter 8, pages 1-24, 8, typed manuscript with holograph corrections. Titled “Forrest or Bragg,” “A Birthday Party.” (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Prose-Biography (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Bedford Forrest and His Critter Company (12 of 26). Chapter 9, pages [1]-33, 33, 33-B, 34-39, 1 unnumbered page, 6, 1 unnumbered page, 17, 4 unnumbered pages, 22, 25-27, 27, 27, 30, holograph and typed manuscript with holograph corrections. Titled “Separating Grant from His Base.” (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Prose-Biography (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Bedford Forrest and His Critter Company (12 of 26). Chapter 10, pages [1]-27, 29-42, 42a, 43, typed manuscript with holograph corrections. (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Prose-Biography (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Bedford Forrest and His Critter Company (13 of 26). Chapter 11, pages 1-14, typed manuscript with holograph corrections. Titled “The Middle Tennessee Campaign.” (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Prose-Biography (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Bedford Forrest and His Critter Company (14 of 26). Chapter 12, pages 1-10, 10, 11-22 (plus 3 unnumbered pages), typed manuscript with holograph corrections. Titled “Rats In The Wall,” “Chicamauga.” (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Prose-Biography (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - Bedford Forrest and His Critter Company (15 of 26). Chapter 13, pages [1]-9, 9a, 9b, 10-13, typed manuscript with holograph corrections. Titled “Chicamauga – The First Day.” (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Prose-Biography (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - Bedford Forrest and His Critter Company (16 of 26). Chapter 14, pages [1]-22, typed manuscript with holograph corrections. Titled “Chicamauga – The Second Day.” (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Prose-Biography (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - Bedford Forrest and His Critter Company (17 of 26). Chapter 15, 13 unnumbered pages typed manuscript with holograph corrections. Titled “Forrest’s Country – His Stomping Grounds.” (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Prose-Biography (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - Bedford Forrest and His Critter Company (18 of 26). Chapter 16, pages 275-277, 1 unnumbered page, 282, 282 (plus 1 unnumbered page), holograph and typed manuscript with holograph corrections. Titled “‘Sookey’ Smith Does Not Reach Sherman.” (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Prose-Biography (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - Bedford Forrest and His Critter Company (19 of 26). Chapter 18, page 308 (plus 2 unnumbered pages), holograph and typed manuscript. (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Prose-Biography (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - Bedford Forrest and His Critter Company (20 of 26). Chapter 20, 1 unnumbered page typed manuscript with holograph corrections. (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Prose-Biography (Box 9, Folder 25)
    - Bedford Forrest and His Critter Company (21 of 26). Chapter 21, page 344 (plus 1 unnumbered page), holograph and typed manuscript with holograph corrections. (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Prose-Biography (Box 9, Folder 26)
    - Bedford Forrest and His Critter Company (22 of 26). Chapter 22, 2 unnumbered pages typed manuscript, titles only – “Gunboats and Hoss Critters,” “Nashville,” “The Invisible Empire.” (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Prose-Biography (Box 9, Folder 27)
    - Bedford Forrest and His Critter Company (23 of 26). Chapter 25, pages 394-395, 397a, 394, 398, typed manuscript with holograph corrections. (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Prose-Biography (Box 9, Folder 28)
    - Bedford Forrest and His Critter Company (24 of 26). Chapter 26, pages 399-401, typed manuscript with holograph corrections. Titled “In A Funeral Hack.” (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - Prose-Biography (Box 9, Folder 29)
    - Bedford Forrest and His Critter Company (25 of 26). Notes for Bibliography, 1 page typed manuscript. (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - Prose-Biography (Box 9, Folder 30)
    - Bedford Forrest and His Critter Company (26 of 26). Maps, 2 hand-drawn maps. (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - Essays-Published (Box 9, Folder 31)
    - “The Approach of the Southern Writer to His Material,” pages [1]-4 typed manuscript, published, 1936 (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - Essays-Published (Box 9, Folder 32)
    - “The Backwoods Progression,” pages 3-20 typed manuscript, published 1933. May have been originally titled “Southern Backwoods” (Tate letter, May 15, 1933). (Box 9, Folder 32)
  - Essays-Published (Box 9, Folder 33)
    - “Fiction and the Essence of Things: Stephen Crane’s ‘The Open Boat.” 1 page typed manuscript, appears to be an early outline of ideas for this article, published, 1966 (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - Essays-Published (Box 9, Folder 34)
    - “The Hind Tit.” Pages [1]-15 typed manuscript with holograph corrections, published, 1930 (Box 9, Folder 34)
  - Essays-Published (Box 9, Folder 35)
    - “A Partial Reading of Parade’s End or The Hero as an Old Furniture Dealer.” Pages 77-95, appears to be a photocopy of proof with editor’s notes and typesetting notes, marked “Mr. Lytle’s copy.” Published, 1981 (Box 9, Folder 35)
  - Essays-Published (Box 9, Folder 36)
    - “The Working Novelist and the Mythmaking Process.” Pages 3-10, 13-14, 16 typed manuscript with holograph corrections, published, 1959 (Box 9, Folder 36)
  - Essays-Unpublished (Box 9, Folder 37)
    - “The American University.” Pages [1]-5, typed manuscript with holograph annotation, paper written for English III at Vanderbilt, May 30, 1924 (Box 9, Folder 37)
  - Essays-Unpublished (Box 9, Folder 38)
    - “A Medley: History and Myth and the Artist.” Pages 1-24, 1-16, 14, 17, 17a, 17aaa, 18-24, 1-17, 1-5, 8-20, [1]-6, 9-11, [1], 3-6, 8-9, [1]-6, 5-6, 7, 9 (plus 2 unnumbered pages), holograph and typed manuscript with holograph corrections in several drafts, with variant titles “A Habitable Garden,” “A Myth In A Garden,” and “Myth In The Mind Of The Writer.” Written 1982 or later. (Box 9, Folder 38)
  - Essays-Unpublished (Box 9, Folder 39)
    - “On The Problem of Farm Tenantry.” Pages [1], 4, [1]-5 typed manuscript with holograph corrections, 2 drafts, about the Bankhead-Jones bill and the tenant question, [1936]. (See letter of October 29, 1936 from Manson Radford) (Box 9, Folder 39)
  - Essays-Unpublished (Box 9, Folder 40)
    - “The Plumed Serpent and the White Elephant.” Pages [1]-15 typed manuscript with holograph corrections, probably written c., 1976 (Box 9, Folder 40)
  - Essays-Unpublished (Box 9, Folder 41)
    - “Principles Make the Plans.” Pages [1]-7 typed manuscript with holograph corrections, probably written in the 1930s. (Box 9, Folder 41)
  - Essays-Unpublished (Box 9, Folder 42)
    - “The Unclean Lips.” Pages [1]-5, 8-13, 13-15 typed manuscript with holograph corrections, probably written in the 1980s. (Box 9, Folder 42)
  - Novels (Box 9, Folder 43)
    - At The Moon’s Inn (published 1941). (1 of 10) Pages [1]-15, typed manuscript with holograph corrections. (Box 9, Folder 43)
  - Novels (Box 9, Folder 44)
    - At The Moon’s Inn. (2 of 10) Pages 4, 6-12, 12-14, 14-15, (plus 3 unnumbered pages), typed manuscript with holograph corrections. (Box 9, Folder 44)
  - Novels (Box 9, Folder 45)
    - At The Moon’s Inn. (3 of 10) Pages 19-31, typed manuscript with holograph corrections. (Box 9, Folder 45)
  - Novels (Box 9, Folder 46)
    - At The Moon’s Inn. (4 of 10) Pages 45, 47-80, typed manuscript with holograph corrections. (Box 9, Folder 46)
  - Novels (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - At The Moon’s Inn. (5 of 10) Pages 6, 8-24, 23-42, 42, 42-44, 44-46, 49-54, 54a, 55-58, 53-57, 57-59, 59-61, 72-74, typed manuscript with holograph corrections. (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Novels (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - At The Moon’s Inn. (6 of 10) Pages 77, 79, typed manuscript with corrections. (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Novels (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - At The Moon’s Inn. (7 of 10) Pages 152-153, 153, 155, typed manuscript with corrections. (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Novels (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - At The Moon’s Inn. (8 of 10) Pages 266-270, 273-299, 299a, 300-301, 301a, 302- 306, typed manuscript with holograph corrections. (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Novels (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - At The Moon’s Inn. (9 of 10) Pages 308-318, 320-328, typed manuscript with holograph corrections. (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Novels (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - At The Moon’s Inn. (10 of 10) Miscellaneous unnumbered pages, holograph and typed manuscript with holograph corrections. (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Novels (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - The Long Night. (6 of 10) Page proofs, pages [6]-15, 17-37, 37-50, with editor’s notes and markings. (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Novels (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - The Long Night. (7 of 10) Page proofs, pages 51-100, with editor’s notes and markings. (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Novels (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - The Long Night. (8 of 10) Page proofs, pages 101-150, with editor’s notes and markings. (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Novels (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - The Long Night. (9 of 10) Page proofs, pages 151-153, with editor’s notes and markings. (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Novels (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - The Long Night. (10 of 10) Page proofs, pages 175-177, 188, 193, 200, 212-248, 252, 254-256, 280, 305-307, 309-310, 312, 319-322, with editor’s notes and markings. (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Novels (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - The Velvet Horn (published 1957). (1 of 2) 1 page typed manuscript, probably an early draft. (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Novels (Box 10, Folder 13)